Kyle Tomlin O'Dore

1812 N 40th St, Apt B, Seattle WA 98103-8352 | 206.434.9661 | kyleodore@gmail.com | kyleodore.dev

Objective

To offer a working and learning mindset that will fight through tough challenges and obstacles to complete goals and learn in the process. To work and develop team skills in a tech environment and to use the hands-on work to improve skills and gain experience in the presence of an experienced workforce. Build a network through mentors and interns for future reference and connections.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - MGM TECHNOLOGY PARTNERS GMBH

JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

Đà Nẵng, Việt Nam

- · Currently working as a full team member on mgm-tp's internal project Timension. A time/project/employee management product for all 700+ employees to use.
- · Primarily a backend developer using JpaRepository, in addition to Java Spring Boot, but will also work on the frontend with React Typescript, utilizing Axios for HTTP requests to the backend.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN – FPT USA CORP.

JUNE 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Tukwila, WA, USA

- · Designed, presented and got buy off from Project Manager, Lead Developer and rest of team of a new design for an existing Node|S based WebApp.
- · Under guidance of the Lead Developer and Project Manager implemented the UX of the new design including changes to the menu, header and general style, layout and functionality of the app. Drove feature(s) through SDLC (software development life cycle), from design planning, implementation, testing to being released to production, ensuring a bug free and smooth user experience for the end user.
- · Participated in daily SCRUM meetings and gained experience and familiarity in the SCRUM, SAFe and Agile processes.
- · Strengthened knowledge of Javascript, CSS and NodeJS related templates, frameworks and libraries such as Pug/Jade, Express, Underscore, JQuery and Bootstrap. Increased experience with GitLab and Microsoft's Azure Cloud Computing Service for source control and product development. Worked with unfamiliar code to understand the underlying functions of the WebApp and JSON and XML data to be able to expand and modify old design and functionality of the WebApp.
- · Laid the groundwork for future updates to include an API that was under production during the internship, expanding the usability of the WebApp through lazy loading.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON (CLASS OF 2021) – SEATTLE, WASHINGTON

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

Bachelors of Science

- · Major: Computer Science (Planned) | Backup Major: Informatics (Planned).
- Related coursework: CSE 142, 143 (Introduction to Java Programming I, II), 3.5 in CSE 414 (Databases), 4.0 in COM 200 (Introduction to Communication), 3.5 in MATH 125 (Calculus II), 3.9 in English 111 (Composition: Literature). Current GPA: 3.46

Skills & Awards

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- · Self-taught in HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Pug, React, TypeScript, Java, spring boot and experimented with Ruby and Ruby on Rails.
- · Familiar with Azure and AWS, Git Source Control, and Eclipse, Visual Studio Code and IntelliJ.
- · Introductory level Object Oriented Programming in Java (CSE 142 and 143 at the University of Washington).
- Databases class on Amazon ec2, SQL Server (with Azure), SQLite, SQL, SQL++, Relational Databases, schema, logical, and physical design and building efficient and optimal database systems. (CSE 414 at the University of Washington)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Proficiency in the Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, OneNote).
- · Active user of Discord and Slack for team communication.

LEADERSHIP

· Swim Team Captain (4 years), Volleyball Team Captain (2 years), Self-Created Service Group Leader (2 years), Student Representative Council Executive (2 years, Activities Coordinator then President), Operation Smile (2 years, vice then group leader for school), Facilitator for Unite UW (2 times).

LANGUAGES

• English (Native Speaker), Vietnamese (Fluent), Spanish (Beginner).

References available upon request